♪
Alice: GO ON, THEN.
HOWEVER, IF I DETECT
EVEN A TRACE OF DECEIT
IN YOUR WORDS...
I SHALL END YOUR LIFE.
( Kirito gasps )
FINE BY ME.
YOU SHOULD DO
WHAT YOU THINK IS RIGHT,
AS LONG AS YOU’RE NOT
JUST BLINDLY FOLLOWING ORDERS.
( Alice groans )
Kirito: I SAY THAT,
’CAUSE YOU WON’T KNOW
THE DIFFERENCE.
YOU DON’T REALIZE IT,
BUT EVERYTHING YOU’VE
BEEN FIGHTING FOR AS A KNIGHT
WAS PLANTED IN YOUR HEAD
BY SOMEONE ELSE.
EVERYONE KNOWS THE STORY,
THAT YOU KNIGHTS
WERE CALLED DOWN FROM HEAVEN
BY ADMINISTRATOR,
THE PONTIFEX OF THE CHURCH,
TO MAINTAIN ORDER IN THIS WORLD
AND DOLE OUT JUSTICE.
BUT BEING SUMMONED’S
THE OLDEST MEMORY
YOU KNIGHTS HAVE.
THINK BACK. DO YOU REMEMBER
WHAT HEAVEN WAS LIKE?
OR YOUR CHILDHOOD?
OR YOUR PARENTS?
Alice: WELL, NO. OF COURSE NOT.
OUR MEMORIES OF HEAVEN
HAVE BEEN SEALED.
I WAS TOLD
THE GODDESS STACIA DOES THAT
THE MOMENT WE ARE SUMMONED HERE.
Kirito: YOU GOT THE PART
ABOUT YOUR MEMORIES
BEING SEALED RIGHT,
BUT STACIA ISN’T THE ONE
WHO DID THAT TO YOU.
IT WAS THE PONTIFEX,
AND SHE DIDN’T BLOCK
MEMORIES OF HEAVEN,
BUT YOUR MEMORIES OF HERE.
ALL YOU KNIGHTS
WERE BORN AND RAISED HUMAN
RIGHT HERE IN THIS WORLD.
YOU HAVE A HUMAN NAME,
ALICE ZUBERG.
YOUR FOLKS RAISED YOU
IN A TINY VILLAGE UP NORTH
CALLED RULID.
( Alice gasps )
Kirito: WHEN YOU WERE 11,
YOU WENT TO EXPLORE A CAVE THAT
RAN THROUGH THE END MOUNTAINS
TO THE DARK TERRITORY.
WHEN YOU CAME OUT
THE OTHER SIDE,
YOU TOUCHED
THE GROUND ON ACCIDENT.
YOU TRESPASSED
ON THE DARK TERRITORY.
YOU BROKE THE LAW.
♪
( Alice gasps )
ALICE ZUBERG.
I HAVE A HUMAN NAME?
THE END MOUNTAINS A-AND RULID.
I CANNOT REMEMBER, NONE OF IT.
Kirito: YEAH, WELL,
DON’T FORCE YOURSELF.
YOU’LL END UP LIKE ELDRIE.
Alice: IT IS
TOO LATE TO STOP NOW!
GO ON.
TELL ME EVERYTHING.
( singing in Japanese )
♪
♪ PROUD OF MYSELF ♪
Kirito: YOUR FATHER’S
THE VILLAGE ELDER OF RULID.
HIS NAME’S GASFUT ZUBERG.
I DON’T KNOW YOUR MOM’S NAME,
BUT, LIKE I TOLD YOU BEFORE,
YOU HAVE A LITTLE SISTER.
I MET HER. HER NAME’S SELKA.
Alice: SELKA.
Kirito: EVER SINCE YOU
WERE TAKEN AWAY BY THE CHURCH,
SHE’S BEEN WORRIED SICK.
WHEN YOU LIVED IN RULID,
YOU WERE A SISTER-IN-TRAINING
AND REALLY GOOD
AT THE SACRED ARTS.
NOW SELKA’S
A SISTER-IN-TRAINING, TOO,
AND SHE’S WORKING HARD TO GET
AS GOOD AT THE ARTS AS YOU.
Alice: YOUR GOAL, AS YOU STATED,
WAS NOT TREASON
AGAINST THE CHURCH,
BUT TO BRING
THE PONTIFEX TO JUSTICE
AND PROTECT
THE HUMAN REALM, YES?
Kirito: YEAH. THAT’S THE PLAN.
Alice: AND YET
WE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
HAVE A DUTY TO PROTECT
THE HUMAN REALM AS WELL.
WE DEFEND IT AGAINST INVASION
BY THE DARK TERRITORY
AT ALL COSTS.
IF YOU MANAGE TO DEFEAT
ALL OF THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
AS WELL AS SLAY
THE PONTIFEX HERSELF,
WHAT THEN? THERE WOULD BE
NO ONE TO PROTECT THIS REALM.
Kirito: WELL,
LET ME ASK YOU THIS.
IF THE DARK TERRITORY INVADES
AND ALL OF YOU KNIGHTS
HIT ’EM FULL FORCE,
THAT’S ONLY GONNA BE, WHAT,
A LITTLE OVER 30 OF YOU?
DO YOU HONESTLY THINK
THAT’S ENOUGH TO BEAT ’EM BACK?
( Alice sighs )
Bercouli: PRIME SENATOR,
YOU NEED TO TALK TO THE PONTIFEX
ABOUT THE DARK TERRITORY.
EVERY DAY,
THEIR ARMY GETS BIGGER.
IT’S A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE THEY ATTACK.
I’M WORRIED THERE’S
NOT ENOUGH OF US KNIGHTS
TO TAKE ’EM ALL ON.
Chudelkin: THAT’S YOUR PROBLEM!
YOU ARE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS,
SO USE YOUR BRAINS,
AND FIGURE IT OUT YOURSELF!
( gasps )
WE ARE DONE TALKING ABOUT THIS.
TRUST IN THE PONTIFEX,
DO AS YOU’RE TOLD,
AND ALL WILL BE FINE. HONESTLY!
( Bercouli sighs )
Alice: ACTUALLY, YOU’RE RIGHT.
EVEN UNC--OR, RATHER,
COMMANDER BERCOULI
HAD MISGIVINGS ABOUT
OUR NUMBERS COMPARED TO THEIRS.
ASIDE FROM US KNIGHTS,
THE HUMAN EMPIRE
DOES NOT HAVE
AN ARMY AT THE READY,
SHOULD WAR BREAK OUT.
Kirito: I KNOW, AND THE REASON
WE DON’T HAVE AN ARMY
IS ADMINISTRATOR’S FAULT.
YOU KNOW WHY THAT IS?
IT’S ’CAUSE SHE’S SCARED THAT,
IF THE PEOPLE HAD WEAPONS,
THEY COULD ALL
RISE UP AGAINST HER.
IF A WAR HAPPENS, THE NOBLES ARE
SUPPOSED TO PROTECT THE WEAK,
BUT SHE LET THE UPPER CLASS
GET LAZY AND CORRUPT.
THEY JUST CARE
ABOUT THEMSELVES NOW.
THIS WORLD’S
RUNNING OUT OF TIME,
BUT IT STILL HAS A CHANCE.
IF WE CAN GET THE WORD OUT
BEFORE THE ARMIES OF THE DARK
SHOW UP, WE CAN FIGHT.
WITH ENOUGH PEOPLE,
WE CAN BUILD OUR OWN ARMY.
Alice: THAT IS IMPOSSIBLE!
AN ARMY?
YOU JUST SAID
HOW CORRUPT THE NOBLES ARE!
THEY WOULD PROTECT THEIR OWN
INTERESTS BEFORE ANYONE ELSE.
Kirito: YEAH, SOME OF ’EM,
BUT THEY’RE
JUST A SMALL GROUP OF PEOPLE.
NOT EVERYONE
THINKS LIKE THEY DO.
THE LOWER-CLASS NOBLES
AND COMMONERS
WOULD JOIN THE FIGHT
IN A HEARTBEAT.
Alice: THE COMMONERS, TOO?
Kirito: UH-HUH. ALL WE DO
IS HAND OUT THE WEAPONS
YOU GUYS HAVE GOT STASHED
HERE IN THE TOWER.
THEN WE TEACH EVERYONE
THE SAME SWORD SKILLS
AND SACRED ARTS
YOU KNIGHTS KNOW.
IF WE DO THAT, WE COULD
BUILD AN ARMY IN A YEAR OR SO.
THING IS, AT THIS POINT,
IT CAN’T HAPPEN IF THE PONTIFEX
IS STILL IN CHARGE.
YOU KNOW WHAT SCARES HER MORE
THAN THE FORCES OF THE DARK?
IT’S PEOPLE HAVING FREE WILL.
IF SHE CAN’T HAVE AN ARMY LOYAL
TO HER, THERE WON’T BE AN ARMY,
SO I SAY WE THROW A COUP.
IF WE CAN BRING DOWN
ADMINISTRATOR,
WE’LL FREE ALL THE PEOPLE.
THEN, WE CAN USE
THE TIME WE GOT LEFT
TO TRAIN THEM ALL TO FIGHT,
AND, WITH ANY LUCK,
WE’LL HAVE AN ARMY BIG ENOUGH
TO STOP THE INVASION.
Alice: THE FACT
THESE MINIONS ARE HERE,
THAT ALONE IS PROOF
OF THE CONTEMPT
THE PONTIFEX HAS FOR US KNIGHTS,
HER MOST LOYAL SERVANTS,
AND THE PEOPLE.
( wind blowing )
- ALL RIGHT, THEN.
- ( Kirito gasps )
Alice: I’LL HELP
UNDER ONE CONDITION.
I WANT YOUR WORD THAT,
WHEN I REGAIN MY MEMORY,
I WILL GET TO SEE
MY SISTER SELKA AGAIN.
( Kirito grunts )
YEAH, OF COURSE. YOU WILL.
IT’S JUST,
WHEN YOU DO GET IT BACK,
YOU’RE NOT GONNA BE
WHO YOU ARE RIGHT NOW ANYMORE.
ALICE SYNTHESIS THIRTY,
THE INTEGRITY KNIGHT,
WILL BE GONE,
AND ALL THE MEMORIES
YOU HAVE NOW WILL BE GONE.
YOU’LL GO BACK
TO BEING ALICE ZUBERG,
THE GIRL
FROM A VILLAGE UP NORTH.
Alice: SELKA.
SELKA. ( gasps )
♪
I CANNOT REMEMBER
HER FACE OR HER VOICE,
BUT WHEN I SAY HER NAME,
IT IS FAMILIAR TO ME.
MY LIPS, THROAT, AND HEART,
THEY REMEMBER.
I USED TO SAY THAT NAME
ALL THE TIME.
SELKA. SELKA.
♪
I KNOW IN MY SOUL
I HAVE A FAMILY...
A FATHER, A MOTHER, A SISTER,
MY OWN FLESH AND BLOOD...
SOMEWHERE OUT THERE,
UNDER THE STARS.
( sobbing )
( sobbing continues )
WHEN YOU SAID BEFORE
THAT WE KNIGHTS WERE NOT CALLED,
BUT CREATED BY THE PONTIFEX,
IT CONFIRMED
WHAT I HAVE SUSPECTED.
THIS BODY,
THE ONE I HAVE BEEN OCCUPYING
FOR THE PAST SIX YEARS,
WAS STOLEN FROM ANOTHER.
I KNOW THAT NOW.
THEREFORE, I SHALL RETURN
WHAT WAS STOLEN.
IT IS WHAT SELKA, HER PARENTS,
AND YOUR FRIEND WOULD WANT.
I AM SURE YOU WOULD WANT THAT
AS WELL, YES?
Kirito: WELL, YEAH.
Alice: BUT FIRST
I HAVE ONE FAVOR TO ASK.
- Kirito: WHAT?
- Alice: IF YOU WOULD,
BEFORE YOU RETURN
THE ORIGINAL ALICE’S MEMORY,
I WOULD LIKE YOU TO
ACCOMPANY ME TO RULID VILLAGE.
I WISH TO VISIT THERE,
BUT I DO NOT WANT TO BE SEEN,
JUST OBSERVE.
AND, IF YOU WOULD, PLEASE
POINT SELKA AND MY FAMILY OUT.
GRANT ME THAT,
AND I WOULD BE MOST GRATEFUL.
Kirito: SURE.
YOU GOT IT. I SWEAR...
BEFORE WE RESTORE YOUR MEMORY,
I’LL TAKE YOU BACK
TO RULID TO SEE ’EM.
Alice: YOU HAD BETTER.
♪
( sighs )
FROM THIS MOMENT ONWARD,
I SHALL PROTECT THE HUMAN EMPIRE
AND ITS CITIZENS IN EARNEST.
I, ALICE SYNTHESIS THIRTY,
HEREBY ABANDON MY RANK
AS AN INTEGRITY KNI--
- ( groaning )
- ( Kirito gasps )
♪
WHAT’S WRONG?
( Alice shrieks )
Kirito: ALICE!
Alice: KIRITO.
( Kirito gasps )
( Alice gasping )
Kirito: LET ME SEE.
( gasps )
IT LOOKS LIKE A...
BAR CODE!
WHAT THE HELL?
- ( gasps )
- ( Alice gasping )
MY EYE, IT BURNS SO.
I SEE SYMBOLS, WORDS.
Kirito: DON’T THINK
ABOUT ANYTHING!
HURRY! CLEAR YOUR MIND!
WHAT’S HAPPENING IS,
WHEN YOU DEFIED THE CHURCH,
IT TRIGGERED
SOME KIND OF MENTAL BARRIER.
THAT’S WHAT’S CAUSING THE PAIN,
AND, IF YOU KEEP
THINKING ABOUT IT,
YOUR EYE WILL EXPLODE.
Alice: HOW CRUEL.
NOT ONLY ARE MY MEMORIES
TAMPERED WITH,
BUT MY WILL, EVEN THAT.
WHOEVER DID THIS IS EVIL.
TELL ME, IS THE ONE
WHO BURNED THESE--
THESE WORDS ONTO MY EYE,
WAS IT HER?
WAS IT THE PONTIFEX?
Kirito: NO.
I DON’T THINK IT’S HER.
IT’S A CREATOR, WATCHING
THIS WORLD FROM THE OUTSIDE,
LIKE A GOD, BUT NOT LIKE
THE ONES IN YOUR CREATION STORY.
Alice: A GOD?
WE KNIGHTS ARE THEIR SERVANTS.
WE HAVE FOUGHT ENDLESSLY
IN THEIR NAME.
WE PROTECT THEIR WORLD.
YET THEY DO NOT EVEN TRUST US.
THEY TOOK MY MEMORIES
OF MY FAMILY AND SISTER.
THEY CAST
THIS DIABOLICAL HEX ON ME
TO ENSURE MY SERVITUDE TO THEM.
I AM NOT A PUPPET!
EVEN IF I AM
THE CREATION OF ANOTHER ENTITY,
MY MIND IS MY OWN,
AND I WILL PROTECT THIS WORLD
AND ALL THE PEOPLE IN IT!
REGARDLESS WHAT THEY WANT,
THAT IS MY MISSION!
Kirito: ALICE.
Alice: KIRITO...
TO BREAK THIS,
I NEED YOU TO HOLD ME.
Kirito: SURE.
( Alice gasps )
HEAR ME, ADMINISTRATOR
AND YOU HEARTLESS GODS.
FOR THE SAKE OF MY MISSION
AND THIS WORLD,
I HEREBY RENOUNCE YOU!
( door creaks )
- Woman: EUGEO.
- ( Eugeo gasps )
Woman: EUGEO!
♪
YOU MUST BE COLD.
COME ON.
IT’S WARMER HERE. HURRY.
( Eugeo gasps )
MOTHER, IS IT REALLY YOU?
Administrator: OF COURSE IT IS.
NOW, WHO ELSE WOULD I BE?
( Eugeo gasps )
UH, WHERE’S FATHER?
AND MY BROTHERS, WHERE ARE THEY?
( Administrator laughs )
SILLY CHILD!
DON’T YOU REMEMBER?
YOU KILLED THEM ALL.
( Eugeo gasping )
( screams )
( panting )
WHAT HAPPENED TO ME?
HOW DID I GET HERE?
THE LAST THING I REMEMBER
WAS FIGHTING BERCOULI
FROM THE LEGEND.
THEN A LITTLE MAN APPEARED,
CHUDELKIN.
AND, AFTER THAT, I WOKE UP...
BUT WHERE?
IS THIS THE TOP FLOOR
OF THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL?
( gasps )
IF THIS IS THE TOP FLOOR,
THAT MUST BE HER.
♪
( gasps )
Girl: NO, EUGEO! RUN!
( Eugeo gasping )
♪
SHE’S THE PONTIFEX,
ADMINISTRATOR.
NOW’S MY CHANCE.
NO. I CAN’T USE
THE DAGGER ON HER.
I WAS SAVING IT FOR ALICE.
Girl: EUGEO! RUN!
♪
( Eugeo gasps )
( Administrator yawns )
YOU PITIFUL THING.
Eugeo: HUH? "PITIFUL"?
Administrator: THAT’S RIGHT.
YOU LOOK SO MISERABLE,
JUST LIKE A FLOWER
WITHERING AWAY IN A POT.
Eugeo: A FLOWER. M-ME?
Administrator: YES. IF YOU
COULD SEE YOURSELF, YOU’D AGREE.
YOU LOOK PARCHED, STARVING,
Eugeo: FOR WHAT?
Administrator: FOR LOVE.
Eugeo: "LOVE"? NO WAY.
YOU’RE WRONG.
I AM LOVED BY LOTS OF PEOPLE.
Administrator:
YOU’VE NEVER KNOWN
WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE LOVED BY ANYONE.
THAT’S WHY YOU’RE SO SAD.
Eugeo: THAT’S NOT TRUE!
THERE’S MY MOM. SHE LOVED ME.
WHENEVER I HAD A NIGHTMARE
AND I COULDN’T SLEEP,
SHE’D HOLD ME AND SING LULLABIES
TO MAKE ME FEEL BETTER!
Administrator: PERHAPS SHE DID,
BUT WAS THAT LOVE
MEANT ONLY FOR YOU?
YOU KNOW IT WASN’T.
IT WAS WHAT SHE HAD LEFT OVER
AFTER SHARING IT
WITH YOUR BROTHERS.
Eugeo: NO WAY. SHE LOVED ME.
SHE DID. I WAS THE ONE
SHE LOVED THE MOST.
Administrator: YOU WANTED
HER LOVE ALL FOR YOURSELF,
BUT SHE LOVED THE OTHERS MORE.
THAT’S WHY YOU HATE THEM SO.
YOUR FATHER, YOUR BROTHERS,
THEY STOLE IT.
Eugeo: STOP IT. LIAR.
I DON’T HATE MY FATHER
OR MY BROTHERS!
I AM NOT JEALOUS!
Administrator: OH, BUT YOU ARE.
WHY ELSE WOULD
YOU ATTACK THAT BOY?
Eugeo: WHAT BOY?
Administrator:
THE ONE WHO CAME BETWEEN YOU
AND THE RED-HAIRED GIRL
WHO LOVED YOU,
WHO LOVED ONLY YOU.
WHEN THE BOY KIDNAPPED HER
AND TRIED TO DEFILE HER,
YOU WANTED TO KILL HIM.
YOU HATED HIM, BECAUSE HE
TOOK SOMETHING THAT WAS YOURS.
Eugeo: YOU’RE WRONG.
THAT’S NOT--
I-I DIDN’T ATTACK RAIOS
BECAUSE I WAS JEALOUS OF HIM.
Administrator: AND, YET,
HERE YOU ARE ALONE.
NO ONE LOVES YOU.
THEY DECIDED
THEY DON’T NEED YOU ANYMORE
AND ABANDONED YOU. BY NOW,
THEY’VE FORGOTTEN ABOUT YOU.
Eugeo: NO. YOU’RE LYING.
THERE’S STILL
SOMEONE WHO WANTS ME.
ALICE. THAT’S IT!
ALICE STILL NEEDS ME.
- Administrator: ARE YOU SURE?
- ( Eugeo gasps )
DOES SHE LOVE YOU?
DOES SHE LOVE YOU AND ONLY YOU?
( Eugeo gasps )
Administrator:
YOU SEEM TO HAVE FORGOTTEN.
I CAN HELP YOU REMEMBER.
YOU HAVE BURIED THE MEMORY
DEEP WITHIN YOUR HEART,
BUT I CAN UNEARTH IT.
( Eugeo gasps )
( footsteps pattering )
I HAVEN’T SEEN
KIRITO AND ALICE ALL MORNING.
( sighs ) WHERE COULD THEY BE?
( gasps )
AH. ALI--EH?
Kirito: HEY, HE’S GONNA COME
LOOKIN’ FOR US. LET’S GO BACK.
Alice: OH, STOP WORRYING.
WE CAN STAY A BIT LONGER,
JUST A BIT.
♪
Eugeo: NO.
THIS ISN’T REAL.
IT DIDN’T HAPPEN.
Administrator: I TOLD YOU SO.
NOW DO YOU BELIEVE ME?
SHE DOESN’T LOVE YOU,
NOT JUST YOU, AT ANY RATE.
POOR THING. IN FACT,
SHE DIDN’T HAVE ANY LOVE FOR YOU
FROM THE START.
( woman vocalizing )
I’M NOTHING LIKE
THAT GIRL, EUGEO.
I WOULD BE HAPPY TO LOVE YOU.
I’D GIVE YOU ALL OF IT,
JUST YOU AND NO ONE ELSE.
Eugeo: NO ONE ELSE.
Administrator:
NOW COME CLOSER, EUGEO.
I WILL SHOW YOU WHAT LOVE IS,
AND YOU CAN LOVE ME
AS MUCH AS YOU WANT.
IF YOU GIVE ME ALL OF YOUR LOVE,
I WILL GIVE YOU
ALL THE LOVE I HAVE IN RETURN.
AND THE DEEPER
YOUR LOVE IS FOR ME,
THE MORE OF ITS PLEASURES
WILL I THEN SHOW YOU,
PLEASURES BEYOND
YOUR WILDEST DREAMS.
Eugeo: IS THAT REALLY
WHAT LOVE IS ABOUT,
A THING YOU TRADE LIKE MONEY?
IS THAT ALL IT IS?
Tiese: NO, EUGEO.
( Eugeo gasps )
Tiese: THAT’S NOT TRUE.
THAT ISN’T LOVE!
♪
( singing in Japanese )
Alice: DON’T BE FOOLED, EUGEO!
( Eugeo gasps )
Alice: LOVE ISN’T LIKE THAT!
YOU DON’T GIVE YOUR LOVE
TO GET SOMETHING IN RETURN!
- Kirito: EUGEO!
- ( Eugeo gasps )
( singing in Japanese )
( Administrator chuckles )
I KNOW WHAT YOU WANT.
YOU WANT TO FORGET
ALL OF YOUR SADNESS
AND MAKE LOVE TO ME
’TIL THE END OF TIME.
YOU WILL, BUT NOT YET.
FIRST, MY DEAR,
I MUST HAVE PROOF OF YOUR LOVE.
YOU WILL TRUST ONLY IN ME
AND OFFER ALL OF YOURSELF TO ME.
WHEN I TELL YOU WHAT WORDS
TO SAY, YOU WILL SAY THEM.
NOW INITIATE THE SACRED ARTS.
Eugeo: SYSTEM CALL.
Administrator: GOOD.
NOW REPEAT AFTER ME.
"REMOVE CORE PROTECTION."
Eugeo: REMOVE...
AM I DOING THE RIGHT THING?
CORE...
I DON’T WANT TO BE SAD ANYMORE.
I DON’T WANT TO BE ALONE.
Administrator: THAT’S IT. GOOD.
YOU’RE ALMOST DONE.
COME INTO ME,
INTO ETERNAL STASIS.
Eugeo: ...PROTECTION.